拨入电话
8点48分11秒 4109153771
相关 不相关
- 23-16 - Lester 是我
- 23-16. - Yeah, Lester.
- 你在哪儿 - 在巴尔的摩东区盯着Monk
- Where are you at? - On Monk in East Baltimore.
- Marlo谁盯着 - 现在没人盯
- Who's on Marlo? - No one right now.
Marlo最难跟 他太疑神疑鬼 反监视手段也多
Marlo's been the hardest to follow. Too paranoid. Too much counter-surveillance.
别管Monk了
Well, peel off Monk
往Broening路那边开 去海运码头那边
and head out Broening Highway to the marine terminals.
地图44页
Map 44,
坐标G10
grid G-as-in-George 10.
- 44页 - 对 这次是个新地点
-44 - 44. - Affirmative. This is a fresh one.
如果他们去那么远的地方 那里有可能是...
If they're going all the way out there, it might just be...
- 没错 - 这就去
- Damn right. - On it.
23-06呼叫所有特派小组成员 目标最新地址在地图44页
23-06 to all units on this detail. New 20 is map 44.
坐标G10 44页坐标G10
Grid G-George 10. That's 44 G-George 10.
分布在那周围寻找可疑车辆
Flood that grid and look for suspect vehicles.
23-12 收到
23-12. 10-4.
我得晚点才到 我在东北区 需要我继续监视Cheese吗
Take me a while. I'm up Northeast. You want me to stay on Cheese?
不需要 优先赶往新地点 看来我们钓到大鱼了
Negative. New 20 is a priority. Think we're on the main stem.
拨出 4102206558
拨出 4109507802
- 怎么了 - McNulty 开始了
- Yeah? - McNulty? It's on.
- 真的? - 当然
- Yeah? - Oh, hell, yeah.
好的
All right...
拨出 8点51分59秒 4106674609 相关
* When you walk through the garden *
* Gotta watch your back *
* Well I beg your pardon *
* Walk the straight and narrow track *
* If you walk with Jesus *
* He's gonna save your soul *
* You gotta keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
火线重案组 第五季 第九集
the.wire.s05e09
* He's got the fire and the fury *
* At his command *
* Well you don't have to worry *
* If you hold on to Jesus hand *
* And we'll all be safe from Satan *
* When the thunder rolls *
* Just gotta help me keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
"跟活不活该没关系"  ---Snoop
有什么消息
OK, whatchya got?
我们四下寻找 然后Bobby看到了Chris Partlow
We rolled around until Bobby spotted Chris Partlow
车停在离这里两条街远的地方
pulled up on a lot two blocks from here.
我们盯着他 直到Marlo出现
So we sat on him until Marlo posted.
他们谈了会儿 然后Marlo离开了
They talked for a minute, then Marlo bounced.
Chris独自来到个仓库门前 几个白人小子给开了门
And Chris goes to the warehouse gate alone and a coupla white boys open up.
他现在就在里面?
He's inside now?
入口就在前面 是这里唯一能用的门 其他的门都锈住了
Entrance is around front, it's the only working gate. Everything else is rusted up.
- 前面是谁在盯 - 两个小组
- Who's watching the front? - Two units.
他们都下车了 离那里一条街远 能清楚看到出入的人
They're out on foot, a block away, with a clear view of what comes in or out.
要是Chris出来了我们怎么办
So what do we do if Chris rolls out?
让他走 Partlow只是个打手 他来就是为了确保万事无误
Let him go. Partlow is muscle. He's here to make sure it looks right.
如果没问题 Monk或是别的人就会过来
And if it does, Monk or someone else'll come on down.
- Cheese可能也会来 - 所以这里是个补货点
- Cheese, too, maybe. - So this is a re-up.
补货个屁 小子
Fuck a re-up, son.
这里 前不着村后不着店
This, here, in the middle of nowhere...
跟这些混账平时的聚头点相距甚远
Miles from anywhere these mopes meet...
这里是大宗交货点
This is re-supply.
除了Chris以外 任何从那里出来的人
Other than Chris, anybody else that goes in there,
只要是个Stanfield手下的小头目 身上就会带着货
if it's a Stanfield lieutenant he's coming out dirty.
跟着他们回市里 要是他没发现你在跟 就看看他会带你到什么地方
Follow them back to town. If he doesn't know you're on 'em, see where he takes you.
要是被他察觉了 管他妈的
If he catches a scent, fuck it.
把他拦下来 查车缴货
Pull 'em over, jack 'em up and get the dope.
另外Leander 你得把手机抢到手
And you want to snatch the man's cell
在他删掉手机里的任何东西之前
before he has a chance to erase anything.
这案子的证据都在手机里
The case is in the phones...
尽管我们需要联邦窃听法案的授权 才能看里面的内容
Though we're gonna need a title three to take a look at them.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
是时候坦白交待了
Time to 'fess up.
没问题吧
We straight?
我说咱俩说清楚了对吧
I said we straight, right?
- 那些枪是我的 - 具体点 哪些枪是你的 Hill先生
- Them guns was mine. - Which guns specifically? Mr Hill.
去年那些条子从车里搜出来的枪 都是我的
Whatever guns them cops took out the truck last year. They mine.
尽管我碰都没碰过
Even though I ain't touched that iron.
要进局子的又不是你
Ain't you got to do the bit.
鉴于你前科有限 Hill先生 你最多会被判个两三年
With your limited priors, Mr. Hill, you're exposed to two, three years, tops.
你坐牢后会得到足够的补偿 我确信
You'll be well compensated for the time, I'm sure.
反正你对我们也没用了 你都成三条腿了
No good to us no how. You on three legs.
把车里那些枪的构造和型号都记熟 Hill先生
Familiarize yourself with the make and model of the weapons you left in the truck, Mr. Hill.
- 细节尤为重要 - 我都挨枪子儿了还要捡这烂摊子
- The details matter. - I get shot up an' then this shit.
- 你们也太强人所难了吧 - 你要是受不了 就去沃尔玛之类的地方瞧瞧
- Y'all ask a lot, don'tcha? - You can't hack, go down Wal-mart.
看你卧床不起这期间他们谁会鸟你
And see if they take care you while you laid up for a while.
走吧 哥们
C'mon, nigger.
老天 在警局里要是你在前线中了一枪
Jeez. In the department, you take one in the line
他们就给你安排最轻松的活 让你想干多久干多久
they give you light duty for as long as you need,
然后你还可以自己选下一个任务
then you get to name your next assignment.
Marlo的组织纪律更严
Marlo runs a tighter ship.
打开
Open it.
六个冰柜 每柜里面二十包
Six icebox, 20 each.
你点数 我们就等着 你不点 我们就早收工吃午饭
You count, we wait. You no count, we go to lunch early.
23-14呼叫23-06 三号嫌犯进去了
23-14 to 23-06. Suspect number three is in.
- 你确定 - 这辆该死的车我都跟一周了
- You sure? - Been following the damn truck for a week.
- 现在当然确定得很 - 收到
- Should know by now. - Copy that.
虱子是六条腿还是八条腿
Ticks have six legs or eight?
肯定是职位重整
Must have been a readjustment.
说实话 在伦敦上班还不错
London was a sweet posting. I can't lie.
我唯一的遗憾就是没在那里干满三年
My only regret is I didn't get the full three-year tour.
- 多谢 - 从你身上可看不出来
- Thanks. - It's no reflection on you, man.
该死 Gus 他们甚至把在肯辛顿的那栋楼都卖了
Shit, Gus, they even sold the building in Kensington.
我是说 50年前咱们没花什么钱 就买下了那栋楼
We bought that sucker for nothing 50 years ago,
现在芝加哥那边居然卖了几百万英镑
and now Chicago sells it off for a couple million pounds.
资本化 这就是他们所说的
Capitalization, they call it.
这些连锁报业的大佬们根本不在乎 是吧
These newspaper-chain guys just don't give a fuck, do they?
现在你回到魅力之城巴尔的摩 知道他们会把你安排在哪儿吗
Any idea where they're gonna drop you now that you're back in Charm City?
不 暂时不清楚
No, I got no idea yet.
Klebanow约我吃午饭 所以我想应该很快就会知道了
Klebanow wants to have lunch, so I guess it'll come at me, soon enough.
心里有谱没
Up for something now?
看看情况吧
Depends.
我遇到点问题 我要找个...
I gotta problem. I need someone...
资深记者 谦逊 敏锐 谨慎 还要注重细节
A veteran reporter, quiet, subtle, discreet, good with details,
善于藏匿行迹
careful to cover his tracks...
我不管咱们关系有多铁 Gus
I don't care how far we go back, Gus,
我不会帮你杀掉你老婆的
no way I'm gonna kill your wife for you.
你知道Scott Templeton吗 城市版的牛人
You know Scott Templeton? City G.A.
就是跟流浪汉杀手通过话的那个?
The guy talking to the homeless killer?
不认识 他是在我去伦敦之后才上任
Not really. He got hired after I went to London.
你不认识他更好
It's better you don't know him.
不管怎样 不会对他有先入为主的成见
No opinions, one way or the other.
不 我不是想说他什么
No, no, I'm not saying anything.
我不是 我只是需要有新鲜的眼光来看看这家伙
I'm not. I just need fresh eyes on the fella.
仔细的看清他的为人
Just a careful look.
- 他是Whiting的爱将嘛 对不对 - 我说过要谨慎点的 不是吗
- One of Whiting's pets, isn't he? - I said discreet.
- 我真希望你是错的 - 那当然
- I hope you're wrong. - Course you do.
- 刺到我了 该死 - 当然会被刺 这可是倒刺铁丝
- It sticks. Dag. - Course it sticks. It's barb wire.
这玩意就是拿来刺人的
Sticking's what it's s'posed to do.
快点 我可没时间整天耗在这儿
Come on. I ain't got all day.
赶紧的 先把那里的铝条都拿着
Hurry up now. Grab the aluminum strips there first off.
- 我要怎么出去呢 - 爬这破围墙呗
- How am I supposed to get back over? - Climb the damn fence.
一回生二回熟
Do a better job of it second time, I expect.
快趁我们被看到前 把那些钢管拿来
Grab them steel pipes quick before we get spotted.
Robert Ruby
- 欢迎回来 - 谢了
- Welcome home. - Thanks.
我需要Scott Templeton署名见报的 所有文章打印件
I need a global printout on everything under Scott Templeton's byline.
所有的都要 每个版本都要
All of it, every edition.
我是他的粉丝嘛
Hey, I'm a fan.
23-14
23-14.
Monk西行往O'Donnell那边去了 Cheese Wagstaff正在往里开
Monk is westbound onto O'Donnell. Cheese Wagstaff is on the way in.
还有 卡车要开走了 就是我们在装货码头看到的那辆
Also, the truck we saw back on the loading dock is leaving.
那辆是空的 他们已经卸完货了 货现在都在仓库里了
That'd be empty. They've offloaded, it's all in the warehouse now.
我和Bobby继续监视Monk
Bobby and me will stay on Monk.
Karen会跟着Cheese出去 你们俩继续守在大门
Karen'll follow Cheese out, you stay on the gate.
连环杀手的问题暂且撇开不提
Forgetting for a moment our little problem of the serial killer,
我们上任时保证要将暴力犯罪率 压低两位数
we came in promising a double-digit drop in violent crime.
就在州长初选的关头 这数字竟然创了历史新高
Right up on the gubernatorial primary, and we're looking at another record high.
Michael 预算消减让警局寸步难行
Michael, this department has been crippled by the budget cuts.
这一年 我们人手和设备都紧缺
For a year now, we haven't had the manpower or the tools.
- 你现在可都有了 - 现在是有 但这事像艘轮船
- You have them now. - Now. But this thing is a ship,
还是艘超级油轮 又不是随便想转向就转向
a super-tanker. We can't just turn it around like that.
增派巡警
More foot patrols.
增派警车巡逻
More cars on the street.
总得想办法控制啊 妈的
Get a handle on it, dammit.
这些就是无用功
See that's what doesn't work.
派出更多警察好让人们看到 派更多警察出现在街头巷尾
More cops where people can see them. More cops on the pavement,
更多警车呼啸而过 更多警察大张旗鼓
more cops riding past, more cops showing the flag
这样你们就能对外宣称 政府严厉打击犯罪
so that you guys can say you're being tough on crime.
无意冒犯 先生 真正有用的
Respectfully, sir, what works
是致力于树立起警局的威慑力
is committing to building a real deterrent.
我们花时间重整 教手下不要一味追求数据
We take the time to retool, to teach our people not to chase stats,
- 而是作切切实实的警务工作 - 是谁提拔你的 副局长
- but to do actual police work. - Who pulled your string, deputy?
起初就是咱们市长告诉我
I was told by our mayor at the outset
以后不会再作表面功夫和玩数字游戏
that there would be no more Band-Aids, no more stat games...
学校预算缺口让我们措手不及
Then we got hit with the school budget.
也就失去了解决你说的这个系统问题
And lost some of the time we needed to address
所需要的时间
the systemic things you're talking about.
懂没 我们会回归正轨
Understood. We will work back on those,
也会继续支持警局改革 就算在市政厅做不到
and we will support that kind of reform, if not from City Hall
在州政府也会继续 要是有必要的话
then from Annapolis, if need be.
不过眼下 副局长 就在眼下
But now, deputy, right now,
我顶头上司就需要犯罪率下去
my boss needs the crime to go down.
不是三年之后 不是一年之后
Not three years from now. Not even a year from now.
就下个季度 他需要犯罪率降低10%
He needs a ten-percent drop in the next quarter...
否则就没人在上头操刀改革
Or no one is gonna be in a position to reform anything.
发挥创造力吧 先生们
Be creative, gentlemen.
副局长 外面有位探员找你 说有紧急情况
Deputy. A detective's outside for you, says it's urgent.
我和Sydnor找到条新线索
Sydnor and I developed a source
重新监视到Marlo Stanfield的动向
and ran fresh surveillances on Marlo Stanfield.
而且我们即将把他的手下 抓个人赃俱获
And we believe we're about to catch his people very dirty.
- 什么 - Clay Davis的案子结束后
- What? - We wrapped on that Clay Davis thing
我们没有关掉重案组
and instead of shutting Major Crimes down,
而是花了几周时间重新追查Marlo
we took a couple weeks and got back up on Marlo.
加上逮捕令 他就落网了
With the right warrants, he's about to fall.
- 这他妈的怎么办到... - 没时间细说了 Cedric
- How the fuck... - There's no time, Cedric.
一小时之内 我就需要...
In an hour or so, I'm gonna need...
嗨
Yeah?
- Lester - 什么事
- Lester... - What's up?
我们把Monk抓了个现行
We pulled up Monk. Dirty as a motherfucker.
八公斤纯货
Eight keys of the raw.
我们想逼停他的时候 他不得已才停下
No, he jersey-rolled a stop and when we tried to pull him over,
这家伙飙车想逃
he went rabbit on us.
我们在Lafeyette的立交桥边才堵下他
We ran him down on Lafayette, by the overpass.
- 电话你拿到了吧 - 还用说吗  我拿到了
- You got the phone, right? - Yeah, man. I got it.
干得好
Good work.
大功告成
It's down.
我需要派小组逮捕Marlo Stanfield
I need teams to arrest Marlo Stanfield,
Chris Partlow还有Cheese Wagstaff
Chris Partlow, and Cheese Wagstaff.
还需要检察官打电话
I also need someone from our S.A.O. To get on the horn
给巴尔的摩郡政府要张搜查扣押令 去搜查沿河中游地区的仓库
to Baltimore county for an S-and-S warrant on a Middle River warehouse.
对了 还有...
And, oh yeah...
Bunk Moreland
手里有对Partlow的逮捕令
has a warrant on Partlow
因为另一起单独的谋杀案
for a separate homicide.
他迟迟没有行动 就是为了让咱们能一网打尽
He held that back so we could do this business here.
还有什么是你忘了告诉我的 Freamon探员
Anything else you've neglected to tell me, Detective Freamon?
没了 长官 我想你都知道了
No sir. I think you're caught up.
- 喂 - Ronnie 亲爱的
- Hello? - Ronnie, dear.
嘿
Hey...
- 你坐稳了啊 - 怎么了
- Are you sitting down? - Why?
抓他的时候这家伙还想删掉呢
He was trying to erase shit when we tackled him.
在我们拿到签好的搜查扣押令前 看住这地方
Secure this location  until we have written search-and-seizure.
这事都上电视了
Shit's on TV, yo.
收缴市值约1千6百万美元的海洛因
With a street value of almost sixteen million dollars in heroin,
以及对高层毒贩的指控
and charges against high-level traffickers
他们是使毒品在这城市街道中流传的毒源
who were going to put this poison on the streets of this city...
我还用帮你们那件事顶罪不
Do this mean I still gotta take that charge for y'all?
...还有我们的警局坚持不懈的努力
...and perseverance by our police department.
尽管我被告知此案仍在调查当中
And while I am told that this investigation is continuing,
但据我所知
it is my understanding that there is at least one murder warrant
至少有一起谋杀指控 跟此贩毒组织相关
associated with this drug organization,
也有证据表明此组织为
which is believed to have been responsible
一年前多起空屋弃尸案的真凶
for many of those bodies found in vacant rowhouses more than a year ago.
我们并没有放弃那件案子的调查 正如我们不曾放弃
We did not give up on that investigation just as we do not give up trying every day
每日每夜的致力于使这座城市
to address ourselves to the task
重回往日的安居乐业和生机勃勃
of making this city safe and vibrant again.
容我对所有染指毒品交易
Let me just say to all others responsible for the drug trade's
破坏城市安定的人说一句
assault on the welfare of this city,
你们的落网之日即将来临
a day like this is coming for you.
简直爷们毙了
Oh, you are so butch.
我看过毒品对巴尔的摩的危害
I have seen what drugs have done to Baltimore.
毒贩不仅毁灭个人 也伤及家庭
Drug dealers do not just destroy individuals. They destroy families.
- 别忘了提社区 - 他们危害整个社区
- Don't forget the communities. - They destroy entire communities.
今天巴尔的摩的市长 检察官
Today the mayor of Baltimore, our state's attorney,
警局 和社区都异口同声
our police department, and our communities are saying,
"我们忍无可忍" 谢谢
"We have had enough." Thank you.
副局长 我是Alma Gutierrez 来自太阳报
Deputy. Alma Gutierrez, Sun papers.
能说几句吗
Care to comment?
这是个褒善惩恶的好日子
It's a good day for the good guys.
能说得更实质点吗
Could you be a bit more substantive?
上次我上太阳报的时候
Last time the Sun had me in its pages,
- 你们对我无中生有的造谣 - 什么事情
- You had me doing things I didn't do. - Regarding?
说我在某人背后暗箭伤人 去查吧
Something about me stabbing someone in the back. Look it up.
"据信息来源证明
"A source of information
"图片经由手机传输"
"identified the transmission of photographs via cellphone."
这什么鬼意思 "信息来源"
Fuck do that mean? "Source of information."
- 他们指的是有人告密吗 - 他妈的哪会有什么人知道
- They sayin' somebody talkin'? - Who the fuck even know?
我要跟律师谈
I wanna talk to the lawyer.
你也被告谋杀 你那份也写着一样的鬼东西对吧
And you caught a murder, too. Says the same shit on yours, huh?
"据收到的消息
"From information received,"
"调查得出与受害者DNA分析结果相符"
"investigation led to DNA analysis of the victim."
- 他们有DNA证据? - 我的头发吧 我猜是
- They got you on DNA? - My hair, I expect.
还有"据收到的消息" 又是告密那码子事
"From information received." More of that snitchin' shit.
我说 他们从哪儿收到的消息
I'm sayin', where the information come from?
只有我们在场这几个人知道
Onliest people knew is us right here.
- Snoop知道 - 放屁
- Snoop knew. - Shit.
你那个叫Micheal的小子呢 可能是他没管住嘴
What about your young 'un Michael? Maybe it was him ran his mouth.
- 他被条子抓过 是不 - 我做那件事就是为他
- He got picked up, right? - I did that thing for him.
他怎么会说出来把自己也拖下水呢
Why would he talk about it an' put hisself in?
他在街头表现倒是经得起考验
He been tested on the streets.
在局子里就不一定了
Maybe he act different in the rooms downtown.
小子常常乱顶嘴
Boy been throwin' up all kinda backtalk 'bout shit.
- 成天抱怨这抱怨那 - 比如说呢
- Buck' wild about this 'n that. - Like what?
抱怨June Bug和他的哥们被欺负
Cryin' about how June Bug and his people got lit up.
抱怨Omar在道上胡扯 放话让你站出来...
Cryin' about how Omar in the street runnin' his mouth, callin' for you to step to...
- Omar说什么 - 没什么
- Omar say what? - Nuthin'.
Omar放话挑衅你 靠 但这没啥...
Omar tried callin' you out by name. But, shit, it wadn't nothin'...
- 他是怎么说我的 - 没说什么 老兄 瞎扯罢了
- What he say about me? - Nuthin', man. Just talkin' shit.
他叫我的名字? 在道上?
He use my name? In the street?
- 说话 狗娘养的 - 他只是 你知道
- Talk, motherfucker. - He just, ya know...
说你应该挺身站出来
Say that you need to step to and that...
我也不知道 他就是满口胡言
I dunno, he just runnin' his mouth some.
- 他是不是说我孬种 - 全都是放屁 老兄
- He call me a punk? - It was bullshit, man.
- 你不用往心里去 - 你他妈怎么知道
- You ain't need that on your mind. - What the fuck you know about
老子什么事该往心里去 混账
what I need on my mind, motherfucker?
老子的名字成为了道上的谈资吗
My name was on the street.
等我们从这该死的地方出去 你们都给我去街头
When we bounce from this shit here, y'all gonna go down to them corners,
让他们知道 老子从来没听到过这些话
let them people know. Word did not get back to me.
让他们知道Marlo不怕站出来对抗任何人 Omar Barksdale 不管是谁
Let 'em know Marlo step to any motherfucker. Omar, Barksdale... Whoever.
老子的名字不是乱叫的
My name is my name.
不觉得那小子像是会告密的人
Don't see the boy snitchin'.
我也不觉得
Neither do I.
但你准备把自己的未来都赌上吗
But you ready to bet your future on that?
看见了没 McNulty 看看人家
Ya see that, McNulty? Ya see it?
孤军作战 埋头查案 理清线索 然后突然之间
One detective, working the file, running a few things down and bang...
他就逮到真凶了
He's got an arrest.
操 现在Chris Partlow都被关起来了 也许还会有几个目击证人
Shit, now that Chris Partlow's locked up, we might have some witnesses coming forward
来为那些空屋弃尸案作证呢
on those cases in the vacants.
- 把那些案子一口气全破了 - 我们手头只有一件案子证据确凿 老大
- Clear 'em all on paper. - We got the one is all, boss.
今天就一件 明天会更多 怎么得来的
One today, more tomorrow. And from what?
就从Bunk对埋头查案里面来的
From the Bunk just workin' a file.
跟平时一样本分做事 但你呢...
Business as usual. But you...
拿着加班费开着新警车 吆喝着你的监视专案组
With your overtime and your cars and your surveillance detail
还弄些狗屁玩意儿 你的大案有啥进展
and your bullshit, where the fuck are you on your red ball?
没进展
Nowhere.
杀手没再打电话 也没再行凶
Killer stopped calling. Stopped killing, too.
我承认 我毫无进展
I admit it. I'm nowhere.
我们对你这么有求必应 你该跟屁股着火似的焦头烂额
From everything we've given you, fire should be shooting out your ass,
但你没有 你他妈坐得 就好像尖锐湿疣似的
But no, there you sit like a genital wart.
拜托 McNulty 给我查点什么出来
C'mon, McNulty. Show me something.
你现在准备怎么办
So what are you gonna do now?
继续让分局里一半的警力 上街巡逻 捕风捉影吗
Keep half a district worth of manpower on the street, chasing bullshit?
风头会过去的
It'll wind down.
不再有谋杀 不再有失踪 不再有电话
No more killing, no more disappearances, no more calls.
- Marlo都抓捕归案了 - 去他妈的Marlo
- Marlo is in cuffs. - Fuck Marlo.
去你妈的
Fuck you.
Klebanow的办公室里在干嘛
What's going on in Klebanow's office?
计划会议
Planning meeting.
- 提报普利策奖的意见书 - 这么早啊
- Pulitzer submissions. - This early?
重点是我们在年末这段时间
The important thing is that we build on this
要继续为这个报道添砖加瓦 相关连续报道不能减少
through the end of the year, with no falloff of coverage.
不错 还有Scott 我们要开始着手寻找
Exactly. And Scott, we need to start looking
对此事件作出的回应 该被批判的地方
for the points where the response to the problem can be criticized.
抓人痛脚 我明白
The "gotcha". I know.
此时此刻 我们还不能确定 这次系列报道要参选哪个奖项
At this point, we can't tell what category we'll enter with this,
但尤其是对公共服务奖来说
but in public service especially,
能导致政策改变 或立新法案的报道所占分量更重
greater weight is gi ven to stories that result in changes to policy, or new legislation.
所以报道新闻引起的反响 也跟报道事件本身一样重要
So covering the reactions to our stories is as important as the stories themselves.
在年前我们要致力于追踪报道 任何因你对流浪者的专题报道
Until New Year's, we want to hammer at whatever changes or discussions
所产生的变化 讨论 或是行动
or actions result from your coverage of the homeless.
图片也很重要 我们在面对评委会时
And graphics matter. Our presentation must be clean and professional
陈述一定要既简洁又专业
when it goes to the committee.
你们真的认为这报道有望冲击普利策?
You guys really think this has a shot at a Pulitzer?
我的确这么认为 而且事实如此
I do and it does.
我当过几任普利策评奖委员
Being on the Pulitzer board for a couple of terms,
近距离了解过评奖过程
I've seen the process up close.
得奖是有门道的 这些门道由来已久
There's a way of doing these things. Time honored.
就是因为懂这些门道 他们才会花大价钱请我
Knowing how is why they pay me the big bucks.
好吧 我们具体想要表达什么 以我们的报道
All right. What do we want to say exactly? With our coverage.
关于流浪者我们应该持什么观点 我是说 这事很糟
What do we want to say about homelessness? I mean, it's bad.
惨不忍睹 这点毋庸置疑 但这难道不是反映了更严重的动态社会症结吗
It's very bad, granted. But isn't it actually symptomatic of a much greater dynamic...
我们要重寻一个长期以来 被人们所忽视的世界
We want to rediscover a world that for too long has been ignored.
深入审视这些谋杀背后的悲剧 种种漠视...
Examine the tragedy underlying these murders, the neglect...
以狄更斯式的角度
The Dickensian aspect.
正是如此
Exactly.
Alma 我最亲爱的
Alma, dearest.
这句引述Daniels的话 "这是个褒善惩恶的好日子"
This quote from Daniels, "It's a good day for the good guys."
- 他就没说点啥更好的 - 他不配合
- He couldn't come up with anything better? - He wouldn't play.
说我们上次对他造谣
Says we took his name in vain last time we used it.
- 什么时候 - 我们说他在市政厅对Burrell放冷箭那次
- When was that? - When we had him backstabbing Burrell at City Hall?
记得吗
Remember?
我用给Daniels家里打个电话吗 再问问他
Do you want me to call Daniels at home? Try him again?
- 截稿时间过了 Gus - 我把这条引述砍了
- We're past deadline, Gus. - I'll cut the quote.
行
All right.
跟我喝一杯 Jimmy
Drink with me, Jimmy.
这不是就你日思夜想的吗 哥们
This is what you wanted, man.
那我为啥感觉这么不爽
Then why do I feel like shit?
你这是产后忧郁症 小子
Postpartum depression, son.
这是次长征 还没到终点
It's the journey, not the destination...
我们抓到了Marlo Stanfield
We got Marlo Stanfield.
- 连环杀手怎么办 - Marlo就是连环杀手
- What about the serial killer? - Marlo is he.
Daniels想让我参加新闻发布会
Daniels wanted me up there at that press conference.
去那里跟那群得意洋洋的傻逼一起
Up there with all the rest of those preening motherfuckers,
庆祝他们自己立了大功
congratulating themselves on a job well done.
他们所有人 本身就是问题
Part of the problem, all of them.
不过在亮出手铐查获毒品的时候...
Yet when the bracelets come out and the dope is on the table...
我们还管着监视小组
We've still got the surveillance teams.
分局还派警察看守着流浪汉
The districts still have guys watching the homeless,
还有便衣警察装成流浪汉的样子...
undercovers dressed as homeless...
这些破事会结束的
That shit'll end.
操蛋事总会结束
It always does.
好吧
Well...
要是你不跟我共饮同欢
If you ain't gonna celebrate with me,
至少要开车把醉醺醺的我送回家
you're gonna at least chauffeur my drunken ass home.
Shardene也最好给我醒着
Shardene better be awake, too.
因为我Lester Freamon 现在心荡神迷好兴致啊
'Cause I do believe Lester Freamon's in the mood for love...
我告诉你 是Kenard干的
Yo, I'm tellin' you, it was Kenard.
凶杀组警察想抓他 都往他住处去三次了
Murder police been to his crib three times tryin' to catch up with him.
胡扯 Omar是被Pimlico那帮家伙干掉的
Bullshit. Omar got kilt by them Pimlico boys.
他们操着三把AK对着他一顿扫射
They ran up on him with three A.K. S an' jus' blazed away.
- 怎么样啊 战士 - 我也不知道 你说呢
- What up, soldier? - I don't know. You tell me.
我是说 大家都被关起来了对吧 操蛋
I mean, everybody locked up, right? Damn...
对 就因为这操蛋事 明天我需要你干点活 兄弟
Yeah. 'Cause-a that shit, I'm 'a need you for some serious business tomorrow.
- 是我认识的人吗 - Big walter
-Big Walter - Anyone I know? - Big Walter.
- 大鼻子Big Walter? - 不是 瘦的那个Big Walter
- Big-nose Big Walter? - Nah, skinny Big Walter,
老在Calhoun街和Riggs大道那家廉价店 门前闲晃的家伙
the one be right there in front of the Cut-rate on Calhoun and Riggs all the time.
- 他要作目击证人? - Marlo说这个人得消失
- He witnessin'? - Marlo say he need to get got.
所以他说是什么就是什么
So it is, what it is.
你有什么问题吗
You got a problem with that?
没问题
We straight.
你不用带武器
No need to bring your iron.
我给你准备了把没记录的9mm手枪 编号也被刮掉了
I got a clean nine for you with shaved numbers.
我明天晚上来接你
I'll pick you up tomorrow night.
你还好吧
You a'ight?
没事 没事
Yeah, yeah.
那就好
A'ight.
过去五年里 美国已投放150亿美元 用以对抗全世界的
In the last five years, the United States has given 15 billion dollars to fight HIV and AIDS
艾滋病毒和艾滋病 但其中只有部分拨款流入非洲
around the world. But only part of it goes to Africa,
而非洲正是艾滋病毒 和艾滋病肆虐的地方
where there's a huge epidemic of HIV and AIDS.
我是说 全世界有一成人口
I mean, ten percent of the population of the world
居住在撒哈拉以南非洲地区 但却有七成的艾滋病新增病例出自那里
lives in sub-Saharan Africa, but 70 percent of the new AIDS cases are there.
在肯尼亚 每7人中就有1人患有艾滋
In Kenya, one in seven people have HIV and AIDS,
在津巴布韦 每4人中就有1人患艾滋
and in Zimbabwe, one in four people have it,
数据来自纽约人权法律评论杂志
according to the article in the New York Human Rights Law Review.
另外 美国公共卫生部部长发言声明 在那片非洲国家中
Plus, the U.S. Surgeon General has said that there are 22 million people with HIV and AIDS
有两千两百万人罹患艾滋
in those African countries.
在未来十年中 在这些国家中
In the next ten years, more people will die from AIDS
死于艾滋的人数会高于 20世纪所有死于战争的人数总和
in these countries than all the wars in the 20th century,
包括死伤最为惨重的第二次世界大战...
including World War Two, the deadliest war...
感觉怎么样 Bunny
How's it feelin', Bunny?
告诉你 要是我有这小子演讲的口才 当时肯定会引起一番轩然大波
I tell ya, if I had that boy's gift to talk, I'd a really caused a stir.
看看他
Look at him go...
也别太妄自菲薄 他的论述方式也是从你而来
Don't sell yourself short. He's got your way of makin' an argument.
不过幸运的是 他看起来像他继母
Lucky for him, though, he looks like his stepmama.
非洲艾滋防治组织声称 美国的经济支援能对非洲起到极大帮助
And AIDS In Africa said U.S. Money can make a huge difference in Africa
就算是一点小钱也能影响深远
where even very small amounts can go a long way.
人们几乎都认可这些钱有两种花法
There seems to be an agreement that the money should be spent in two ways:
医药治疗和教育防治
Medical treatment and for education and prevention.
然而 该在什么项目上花多少钱
However, there is not an agreement on how much money
仍未得出定论
will be needed and what programs...
- 我们什么时候能出去 - 我还在弄保释候审的事
- When do we bounce? - I'm working on bail reviews.
Cheese可能...
Cheese maybe...
要是他想回他妈妈家去住 保释金会很高 Monk也一样
On a high surety bond, if he wants to put up his mama's house. Monk, the same.
但由于背着谋杀案的逮捕令 Chris不能被保释
But with the murder warrant, there is no bail for Chris,
并且你也很可能不能被保释
and most likely, there's no bail for you,
因为指控里说你是犯罪团伙的头目
as the charging papers portray you at the top of the conspiracy.
我都从不亲自经手毒品买卖 他们怎么能这么说
How can they say that when I ain't go near no drugs at all?
完整的书面证词中说 他们手握着一条消息来源...
The full affidavit says they developed a source of information...
扯淡
Bullshit.
消息来源让他们得知你们之间
A source of information who told them that you communicated with each other
以手机传输图片的方式互通信息 互通加密信息
using photographic transmissions on cellphones. Coded transmissions.
除了我 Chris Monk和Cheese之外 没人知道解密方式
Ain't nobody know about the code 'cept me, Chris, Monk an' Cheese...
但我们却全都被关在这里
An' we all locked up behind this.
其他人甚至连电话都没有 连Snoop都没有
No one else even have a phone. Not even Snoop.
- 除了供应商 - 你相信这个供应商
- No one 'cept the supply. - You trust the supplier?
这个嘛 总有个知情人去告了密
Well, someone knew and someone told.
现在他们收了你的手机 而且还要去申请联邦窃听法案批准
And now they've got your cellphones, and they're going for a title three.
所以他们一直在跟踪我们的手机...
So they was on our cellphones...
不 书面陈述上说 消息来源告诉他们 你们的交货日期
No, the affidavit says the source told them the date of your re-supply,
他们跟踪Monk和其他人去了仓库 又跟着他出来
they followed Monk and others to the warehouse, followed him out,
然后查获了毒品
and found the drugs.
他们正在申请联邦窃听法案授权 并且他们宣称调查Monk的手机
They're going to get their title three and they're saying that by examining Monk's phone,
你的手机 还有其余人的手机 会有证据证实你们是犯罪同谋
your phone, and the others, they're going to prove the conspiracy.
看见了吗 他们没有窃听你们 但现在他们却以电话
You see? They weren't on a wiretap, but now they're using
还有图片作证据把你们全部扯到一块儿
the phones and photographs to link you all together.
那么有谁知道这次交货 有谁知道你们昨天的计划
So who knew that there was a re-supply? Who knew what you all were up to yesterday?
- Snoop - 你相信她
- Snoop. - And you trust her?
还有谁
Who else?
已知的性侵案惯犯 在南区 这三个有可能是嫌疑人
Known sex offenders, Southern district. Three possibles.
- 你要我们去监视他们 - 对 监视个一两天吧
- You want us to sit on them? - A day or two. Yeah.
- 要是没看出什么端倪 我们就换别的 - 行
- If nothing shows, then we'll move on... - OK.
流浪汉死亡
Dead and homeless.
在布鲁克林的Jack大街 Christeson已经到现场了
Jack Street in Brooklyn. Christeson's down there.
- 勒杀? - 事实上是起暴打致死
- Strangle? - Sounds like a beating, actually.
- 手腕上系着红丝带? - 事实上 是条深褐色的
- Red-ribbon tied around the wrist? - Actually, it was more of a burnt sienna
而且还缠在他的那话儿上 老子怎么知道 自己过去看
and it was lashed around his dick. Fuck do I know? Get down there.
Jay 这听上去不像...
Jay, this doesn't sound like...
浪费你时间了么
Waste of your time, huh?
你们今天在这里的所见所闻
That what you have seen here today
象征着市里的学校 在这个领导班子下所取得的进步
is indicative of the progress that city schools are making under this current administration.
我知道州长对巴尔的摩的学校
Now I know the governor has had some harsh things to say
严加指责 但我认为这些指责 不仅只是冷嘲热讽而且还让人失望
about Baltimore schools, but I find that to be cynical and disappointing.
三年级的学生考试成绩上涨了15分 这是个不容忽视的进步苗头
The 15-point jump in third-grade test scores is a trend that can't be ignored.
但我们以前也见过三年级学生分数上涨 市长先生
But we've seen third grade scores rise before, Mr. Mayor.
但这样分数增长的苗头并不能持续到
And it doesn't seem as if any gains in that grade can be sustained
五年级和七年级
into fifth and seventh-grade scores.
Kathy 你知道我们竭力于 让巴尔的摩市产生实质性改变
Kathy, you know, we are committed to substantive change in Baltimore.
你今天在市级辩论中看到的这些孩子
The kids that you saw today in this citywide debate...
他们达到了高中生的水准
They are achieving at a high school level
并且驳斥了对市教育系统的刻板负面印象
and disproving any negative stereotypes about the city school system.
抱歉失陪一下
Could you excuse me for a moment, please?
Colvin警长
Major Colvin.
别叫我警长了
Just Colvin.
事情以那样的方式结束 我一直想向你道歉
You know, I always wanted to say how sorry I am how things turned out.
你对西区所作的实验性改革失败告终 我当时无能为力
There wasn't anything I could have done with your experiment in the Western district.
那件事大家都无能为力
There wasn't anything that anyone could have done with that.
那好吧 市长先生 我想
Yeah, well, I guess, Mr. Mayor...
也没什么需要做的
There's nothing to be done.
C先生 你连市长都认识? 真牛
Mr. C., you know the mayor, too? Dag.
真不敢相信我还会理你 Gus
I can't even believe I'm talking to you, Gus.
在你那样抹黑我之后
After that shit you pulled.
你们这些家伙都是这样 把人家骂个狗血淋头 第二天又跑回来
That's how you all do. Slam somebody an' then come back the next day
跟啥事都没发生过似的
like it never happened.
这都是公事嘛 Nerese
It's jus' bidness, Nerese.
也轮到你看看自己的负面新闻了嘛
It was your turn to read about yourself.
现在 要是Carcetti当上州长 你当上市长
Now, if Carcetti's governor and you become mayor...
Bond会跟你对着干吗 还是他已经这么做了
Is Bond gonna run against ya? Or is he done?
你觉得呢
What do you think?
在Clay Davis这通闹剧过后
After the Clay Davis farce...
我觉得他就算是玩完了
He smells like he's done to me.
有传言说Keiffer也想选市长
There's rumor that Keiffer wants the job, too.
等他要选了再说吧
I'll deal with that as it comes.
这个叫Daniels的家伙怎么样
What about this Daniels fella?
你觉得他准备好统领整个警局了吗
You think he's ready to run the copshop?
不过他对Burrell背后放枪这举动 还真是挺阴损的 我是说...
It's kinda ugly the way he put a knife to Burrell like that. I mean...
我看到那篇的时候还在想 真不知道你们这群家伙怎么想出来的
I read that and wondered where the hell you people got it from.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我直到Burrell下台前都是支持他的
I was behind Burrell until the moment I wasn't.
要是有人在市政厅里对他捣鬼
And if he had someone backstabbing him at City Hall...
我一定会知道
I'd've heard about it.
Daniels这号人物我想都没想过
Daniels wasn't even on my radar.
Daniels没有整过Burrell?
Daniels didn't undercut Burrell?
妈的 后来在大家都知道他的大名之后
At the end, after his name was floated,
Daniels还到处去解释说他根本不想上位
Daniels went around saying he didn't want the job.
说说情况
Talk about it.
这家伙被痛揍了一顿
Well, he's been beat pretty good,
但我看到颈部有擦伤 所以也有可能尝试过扼杀
but I've got neck bruising too, so it could be an attempted strangle.
- 没有红丝带? - 没有
- No ribbon? - Nope.
咬痕呢
Bite marks?
我是没看到
Not that I can see.
- 这家伙好臭 - 他可能是排过便(也有撤离疏散的意思)
- This fuckin' guy stinks. - He probably evacuated.
- 什么 你说他撤走又回来了? - 不 我是说他拉了裤子
- What? He left and he came back? - No, he shit himself.
这不是我那杀手干的 抱歉啊 菜鸟
It's not my guy. Sorry, rook.
这家伙归你了
He's all yours.
州长是否觉得有内容要修改是件麻烦事
Does the governor think that's a problem, something that needs addressing?
请稍等
Hold on a sec...
你拿到海军陆战队的军事记录了吗
You got the military records from the Marines?
他们说至少需要三周
Three weeks at least, they said.
抱歉
Sorry about that.
嘿 Steven 我遇到点问题
Hey Steven, I gotta little problem.
你这个年龄的男人都有点问题
Well, it's common in men your age.
我要去趟沃尔特里德陆军医院 去跟那里的一个老兵谈谈
I need to get into Walter Reed. I gotta talk to a vet down there.
那个说他在交火的时 跟流浪老兵在一起的家伙
The fella that was with our homeless vet when he saw that firefight.
就是Templeton写的那哥们
The one Templeton was writing about.
- 你追以前的新闻干嘛 - 我就是想去跟他谈谈
- Why go back on that? - I just want to talk to a guy.
那个流浪哥们跟我说过名字 说他是那里的住院病人
Homeless fella gave me the name, said he's in-patient down there.
华盛顿邮报曝光过沃尔特里德医院 虐待老兵丑闻
在报纸用连续报道曝光 沃尔特里德陆军医院丑闻后?
After the Post series blew up Walter Reed's shit?
你去一说你是个记者 他们就不会再鸟你了
If you tell them you're a journalist, you're dead to them.
我知道 不过你在那边有认识的人 对吧
I know. You know somebody down there, right?
不是医院那边的人 我有个邻居在伤兵组工作
Not at the hospital. A neighbor of mine is with AW2.
- 什么组 - 军队的伤残士兵项目组
- What? - The army's Wounded Warrior program.
她能帮你进去 只要你不把这事写成报道
She could get you in, if you're not actually writing a piece.
- 我不写 - 那你到底是要干嘛 Gus
- I'm not. - What are you doing, Gus?
挠个痒痒
Scratching an itch.
我真怀念换班派对啊
I do miss the shift-change parties.
你怀念才怪 你一个都不会怀念的
No, you don't. You never missed a fucking one of them.
你们抓Marlo Stanfield那次还是真大快人心
That was one sweet bust you people put on Marlo Stanfield.
用了我给你的电话号码对吧 一听就知道是Lester Freamon的窃听战术
My number, right? I mean, it definitely smells like a Lester Freamon wiretap.
我看了新闻 查获了那么多毒品
I watched the news, all that dope on the table.
我发誓 Carv 我看得都硬了
I swear, Carv, I was fully erect.
你那话儿硬了? 你怎么知道
Your dick got hard? How could you tell?
因为龟头都从你脖子后面伸出来了
'Cause the head was poppin' out of the back of your neck.
说真的 是搞的窃听 对吧
Seriously, it was a wiretap, right?
说真的 我要是知道也不能告诉你 Herc
Seriously, I couldn't fuckin' tell you if I knew, Herc.
你这是什么话 我电话号码白给了?
What're you saying? My phone number wasn't shit?
你他妈想要我怎么说嘛 Herc 你最屌
What do you want me to fuckin' say, Herc? You're the tits.
没有你作出的那点贡献
Without your little contribution,
整个该死的城市 都会堕入切萨皮克湾底
the whole fucking city slips into the Chesapeake Bay.
好点没
Better?
你是在那里长大的?
So you grew up there?
你家是什么时候搬到巴尔的摩的
When did your family move to Baltimore?
Reginald 你在下面吗
Reginald. You down there?
- 在啊 - 到楼梯口来
- Yes. - Come to the steps.
给你带了点东西回来
Got a coupla things for you.
肥皂 除臭剂什么的
Soap, deodorant and the like.
谢谢你 我一直用水槽在洗
Appreciate that. Usin' the washing basin to clean up.
也用同一个水槽在尿
And to pee in.
别担心 我会把它冲洗干净的
Don't worry, I rinse it out.
我在想 最近我要参加个戒毒周年纪念 在开会的地方
I was wonderin'... I got this anniversary comin' up, at the meetin' place.
有时候大家会有些亲朋好友来支持下
Sometimes kin folk come along to show support.
我在想 也许你也能来...
I was wonderin', maybe you could...
我在医院的工作排得很慢 很难挤得出时间
It's hard for me to make plans with my schedule at the hospital.
之后会有个庆祝活动 我在想也许能下厨给你们做点吃的
We got a little celebration after. Thinkin' I could cook us some dinner.
也不是什么豪华大餐
I mean wouldn't be a fancy thing,
就是奶酪通心粉之类的 但我保证你会觉得很不错
mac and cheese, like that, but I guarantee it'll be good to you.
再说吧
We'll see.
好吧
OK.
我姐姐
My sister.
她是个好人
She good people.
熬过很多苦日子 你懂的
Been through a lot though, you know?
- Levy - 你说什么
- Levy. - 'Scuse me?
Levy 辩护律师
Levy. The lawyer.
我知道他是谁
I know who he is.
我没在追查什么律师 我追的是钱的流向
I'm not looking for any lawyers. I'm following the money.
从律师下手查 Levy Brofman Silverstein Cray
Follow the lawyers. Levy, Bronfman, Silverstein, Cray...
所有为高层毒贩干活的家伙
All those guys who take the high-end drug work.
他们收的可不止是诉讼费
They don't just make money off the criminal fees.
- 他是怎么... - 律师是怎么办的?
- How's he... - The lawyers?
他们为所有来自街头的黑钱开路
They make a path for all this street-corner money.
他们告诉黑帮大佬们 怎么把钱转移到海外 怎么拿回来
They showin' all these kingpin motherfuckers how to send it overseas, bring it back,
搞点投资
Invest the shit.
这帮没文化的小混混遇到钱的问题
They the ones who these ignorant ghetto motherfuckers always listen to
总是会听他们的
when it comes to cash money.
这个Levy 老兄 他赚的油水最多
And Levy, man, he got the most grease.
那Levy是通过谁来洗钱呢
So Levy routes it through who?
任何手头有项目或赌局缺现金的人
Anyone who got a project or a game in need of cash.
开发商 集资者 还有像我这样竞选的人
Developers, people lookin' to capitalize, elected folk like myself.
这年头随时都有人缺钱
There's a lotta people need a dollar now an' then...
律师从中抽成
And the lawyers take their cut.
两头都抽成 但我得说
On both ends, though I got to say,
他也只会让你敲他的客户那么些钱
he gonna let you rob one of his clients only so much.
我是说一旦Barksdale或者Joe Stewart 这些肥羊上了钩
I mean once you get a Barksdale or a Joe Stewart on the hook,
你肯定会想往死里阴他们的钱
you want to go deep on they ass.
Levy会让你尝到点甜头 但不会放着让你不收手
Levy'll let you get a taste, but he won't let you run wild.
因为一旦你越过这些狗日的律师 你就能自己牵线搭桥了
'Cause once you get past these motherfuckin' lawyers, you can really play the pimp.
有一次 我钓上个肥羊叫Bell(Stringer)
This one time, I had this fella named Bell
把钱投资在Howard街的公寓项目里
hooked up on this Howard Street condo thing.
把他套死 这样他才没去告诉律师
Got him so that he wasn't runnin' his shit past the lawyer...
老兄 我告诉你 那混蛋被我们狠敲了一笔
Boy, I tell you, we bled that motherfucker...
律师是吧
Lawyers, huh?
那是当然 探员
Most definitely, detective.
我 操 我不过条小鱼
Me? Shit, I'm just small potatoes.
只是名来自巴尔的摩 Walbrook小区的一名打工的政客
Just a workin' politician from Walbrook Junction,
拼命想往上爬罢了
tryin' to make his way from this world into the next.
关于Levy你还知道些什么
What else can you give me on Levy?
就我刚才说的那些 我又不怎么跟他打交道
Nothin' other than what I have. I ain't up in his business or nuthin'.
- 我只是捡些他不要的边边角角 - 胡扯
- I just takin' what he throws. - Bullshit.
你提供点可靠的情报 不然我立马就去找联邦检察官
You got something solid or I'm on my way to the U.S. Attorney.
你还真是个敲诈勒索的行家啊
You ain't nuthin' but a shakedown artist.
这条怎么样...
How's this...
Levy在法院有关系
Levy got someone at the courthouse.
这是当然的
Oh, hell yeah.
Levy多年来都在从法庭里买文件 卖给任何想提前查看的人
Levy been buyin' papers for years and sellin' 'em to whoever needs an early look.
别以为这里面没油水
And don't think there ain't no real money in that.
- 是哪个检察官吗 - 我不知道名字
- A prosecutor? - I don't have a name.
真的不知道 但就我看来 你要是开始盯着那些
Truly I don't, but it seems to me, you start lookin'
总在大陪审团周围打转的人 你就会知道我是对的
at the people hangin' around the grand jury, you'll find I'm right.
现在我知道我交代够了 可以把案子交还给我了吧
Now I know I've said enough to buy my case back.
你知道 你至少可以请一轮吧
You know, you could buy a round, too.
弄疼你了?
I get you?
没 感觉不错 Hubert
Nah, feels good, Hubert.
你很认真 也很专心
You dig in there, you got a mind to.
觉得我的手很不错吗 先生
You admiring my hand, sir?
哦 叫我Gus就好
Oh, call me Gus.
老习惯总改不了口
It's hard to get out the habit.
- 看起来真是栩栩如生 - 没错
- That's pretty damn lifelike. - Yeah.
假体手指 五根都是 每根都可以独立控制
Prosthetic digits. Five of 'em, individually controlled.
我都能抓
I got my key grip...
也能握
And my power grip...
还能捏
My precision grip...
还能用食指指着
And my index point.
这些新模型的大拇指能转动 这点改进作用非常大
These new models got a thumb that rotates, which makes all the difference.
以前只有这一种抓的动作 做什么都靠这个动作
Used to be you just had this one grip, right here for everything.
- 你能比这个不 - 还不行
- You got your... - Not yet.
- 美丽的新世界啊 - 没错
- Brave new world. - Yeah.
介意我录音吗
Do you mind if I?
伤残士兵项目组的女士说 你不会写成报道
The A.W.2 lady says you weren't writin' no story.
不会 我只是来求证 一些已经登报的报道细节
No, I'm just verifying details of one we already printed in my newspaper.
关于你哥们的经历
Profile of your buddy.
Terry
Terry.
是啊 他每过几周就会来看看我
Yeah, he come down visit me every coupla weeks.
从巴尔的摩坐彼得潘巴士过来
He takes that Peter Pan bus down from Baltimore.
从银泉站沿着乔治亚大道走好几英里路
Walks a couple of miles down Georgia Avenue from the Silver Spring terminal.
如你所知 他很不满
He's having some trouble as you know.
你读过那篇文章吗
Did you read the article?
读了 作者有的地方写得不错
Yeah. Man who wrote it got some stuff right.
Terry来的时候很火大 我对他打趣
Terry was pissed, I tried to play it off,
想让他别生气
make him good with it.
报道里哪些地方不实
What did the story get wrong?
事情发生那天 并不是像电影黑鹰坠落里面那样
Well, that day wasn't no Black Hawk Down thing.
你知道 当时情况变得很糟
You know, when shit went bad...
在我失去双手之后 那群阿拉伯的混蛋
After I lost my hands, them Habudabi motherfuckers
在爆炸发生后根本没出现
weren't even around after the shit went off.
他们就是这样
That's how they do.
- 你怎么样啊 Marino - 好得不能再好了
- How you doin', marino? - Outstanding.
我这么问吧 Terry有可能夸大其词吗
Let me ask you this. Could Terry have exaggerated?
为什么不可能呢 如果他是说的时候过于激动
Why not? If he got wound up say...
人要是在战争这种事上谎 肯定是因为没上过战场
You lie about combat because you weren't there.
Terry上过战场 去过两次
And Terry was. Two tours.
他要是想也能编些故事出来 不过那天的事他不会胡诌
He's got stories if he wants 'em. Just not on that day.
他没撒谎 你们在撒谎 很抱歉这么说
He ain't lie, y'all did, sorry t'say.
Kima 你在扯什么鬼话
Kima, what the fuck are you taking about?
我是说你不该让McNulty把你的人手
I'm sayin' you made a mistake letting McNulty
从一个案子调到另一个
run your people from one case to the other.
为什么 这有什么大不了的
Why? What's the big deal?
他们的出勤表 警务报告 都是McNulty搞定的 对吧
Their run sheets, office reports. McNulty covered them, right?
那他妈又怎么样 他们干了警务工作
So fuckin' what? They did police work.
老实说他们干的是真正的警务工作
They did good fuckin' police work, in fact.
你的手下
Your guys...
你训练得很好 Ellis
You coach 'em good, Ellis.
你得告诉他们 等内务调查组的人找上门来
You let them know when I. I.D. Comes callin' that their answer is
他们只能回答什么都不知道
that they didn't know anything about it,
他们只是奉命行事 上交的也是正常的出勤表
that they did what they were told, they turned in clean run sheets,
并且他们并不知道有别的什么人 是把什么表格送上去作员工考核的
and they don't know what anyone else sent upstairs for staff review.
知道啥东西?
Know about what?
你打Colicchio报告的时候 感觉怎么样
When you spoke up on Colicchio how did that feel?
- 感觉糟透了 - 那你可以接受吗
- Like shit. - You OK with it?
我是不得已而为之 Tony迷失了自我 他干了傻事
It was a forced move. Tony was around the bend.
但这样你也可以接受吗
But are you OK with it?
...这里是Q Jams 最嘻哈最R&B的电台 我是你们的女主播Neke...
It's your girl Neke here...
我们的人出没在街头巷尾
We got our peoples in the street.
他们大牌 他们富态 他们女靓男帅 你好啊 Porkchop
What up, Porkchop?
你好啊 Neke 我是你们的男主播Porkchop
What's up, Neke, it's your boy Porkchop...
我们就这么干等着?
We just gonna sit.
我该走了 现在加个油这么贵 我不能在这停着等
I should cut it. With what they charge at the pump, don't make sense to idle.
- 你可以走了 - 去哪儿
- You can go. - Where to?
我是说你可以把车留给我
Sayin' you can leave the car with me.
你这车一直租到晚上 对吧
You rent by the night, right?
我觉得似乎没什么赚头啊
I ain't seen no medium of exchange.
听着 你完事之后 给我停在我接你的地方就行
Look, when you done, leave my short on the street where I pick you up at.
我的天 看看这是谁
Oh, my God. Look at this.
- Bubs - Walon 老兄
- Bubs. - Walon, man...
这位是Fletcher 最近老跟着我的报社记者
This here's my boy Fletcher. Newspaper writer been followin' me 'round.
欢迎你进来坐坐
You're welcome to sit in.
但我得请你尊重每个人的隐私
But I have to ask that you respect the privacy.
不能作笔记 不能录音 今天你听到的都不能说出去
No notetaking, no recorders, what you hear today stays in the room.
没问题 我今天就是为了来陪Reginald
Not a problem. I'm just here with Reginald.
Reginald
Reginald?
我是这家伙他妈的担保人 他都没把教名告诉过我
I'm his fuckin' sponsor and I don't believe I ever got a Christian name out of him.
- Reginald 了不起啊 - 看看你干了什么
- Reginald. Hot shit. - See what you done?
- 我怎么了 老兄 - 来吧
- What, man? - Come on.
我的名字是...
My name is...
Reginald
Reginald.
- 附近大伙都叫我Bubbles - 嘿 Bubbles
- Round the way they call me Bubbles. - Hey, Bubbles.
我是个瘾君子
I'm a drug addict.
在此庆祝我的戒毒一周年
Celebratin' my anniversary.
我的家人今晚不能到场
My people couldn't make it here tonight.
我过去给他们添了不少麻烦
I left a trail of fire behind me.
时间会抚平一切的 我想
Time gonna make it right with them, I guess.
不错 时间会的
That's right, it will.
时间也会让我自己慢慢变好的
Same thing get me right with myself.
几天前 我去德鲁伊山公园散步
Coupla days ago, I took a walk down in Druid Hill Park,
就在太阳下山的时候
right when the sun was goin' down.
你们知道那个时间的光景 夕阳辉洒 暮影西斜
You know how that time be like, with the sun throwin' shadows an' all.
让我想起年少的时候 坐在那个公园里
Got me thinkin' 'bout when I was a young man, sittin' in that park.
你们知道 看看美女 抽抽大麻 灌几口冰啤酒
You know, watchin' the girls, smokin' on a little herb, drinkin' a cold beer.
你们都知道这之后会怎样
You know where this is goin'.
就在那时 我又想再次体会一把那种感觉
I had this moment where, you know, I was wantin' to feel that way again.
我想起你们说过
I remembered, what y'all said,
如果又有复吸的冲动 打给戒毒组里的成员聊聊
if the urge was to come, call a group member up and talk.
我最先想到打给Walon 他是我的担保人
First thing I called Walon up, him bein' my sponsor an' all,
结果他跟摩托俱乐部的人出去兜风去了
turns out he's on a ride with his motorcycle club.
所以我找到了发给大家那张表
So I pulled out that sheet that got passed out...
打了几个电话 没有人接
Dialed a few numbers, couldn't get an answer.
我留了几条留言 但没人回我电话
I left a coupla messages, but nobody called me back.
你没打给我 要是打了 我肯定都跟你勾搭上了 Reginald
You didn't call me. 'Cause I would have got up with you, Reginald.
这事儿准成
You can believe that.
谢谢抬举
Obliged.
总而言之...
Well, anyway...
我没去嗑药
I didn't get high.
看见了吗 我就知道如果当时没忍住 就再也无法回到每日期盼的那份好心情
See, I knew if I did I wouldn't get that good feelin' back that I was daydreamin' on.
说得对
That's right.
这件事让我想到一个朋友
It got me thinkin' about a friend of mine...
那男孩叫Sherrod
Boy named Sherrod.
他的去世在我心里背负了很长时间
I been carryin' his passin' for a long while.
就像公园里的夏日时光那段回忆
Like that memory I had about those summer days In the park.
回想起那个总让我莞然而笑
Thinkin' on that make me smile.
回想起Sherrod却觉得心如刀割
With Sherrod, it's more of a hurt.
现在已没有之前那般痛苦了
But not as... Not so bad like it was.
心怀悲伤并不是可耻的事情
Ain't no shame in holdin' on to grief.
只要你还为其他向往留出空档
As long as you make room for other things, too.
没关系
It's all right.
感谢你们的倾听
So thank you for listening.
- 感谢你们让我分享 - 感谢你分享
- Thank you for lettin' me share. - Thanks for sharing.
我的枪在哪儿
Where my gun?
藏起来了 我们埋伏好再给你
In the trap. You get it when we set up.
有个探员来找你 Greggs 她说叫这名
A detective is here to see you. Greggs, I think she said.
怎么了 有什么事
What? What's the matter?
你怎么知道大家被抓是Walter搞的鬼
How you all even know if Walter behind everybody gettin' jacked?
我是说 你们难道从没想过 这是不是他活该吗
I mean, ain't you all ever wonder if he even deserve any of this shit?
跟活不活该没关系 他死期已到 就这样
Deserve got nuthin' to do with it. It's his time, that's all.
喂 在那条小巷那里停一下 我快被尿憋死了
Yo, pull over in that alley right there. I gotta piss sumpin' fierce.
你最好给我尿在地上那小杯里
You better piss in that cup right there on the floor.
要十个那种杯子才够尿 快靠边停 Snoop
Man, I'm gonna need ten cups. Yo, pull over, Snoop.
又怎么了 小兔崽子 你害羞了?
What now, motherfucker? You shy?
聪明的小鬼 你一向如此
Smart nigger. You always was.
你是怎么知道的
How you know?
你们都教过我 先去踩点
Y'all taught me. Get there early.
为什么 我做错了什么
Why? What I do wrong?
Chris因为帮你做的那件事而进了局子
Chris locked up behind somethin' he done for you.
- 你又被警察抓去市里过 - 我什么都没说
- You downtown with the police. - I ain't say a word.
对你是这么说的 但主要在于你的表现
Yeah, that's what you say. But it's how you carry yourself.
总是不合群 总是对你该执行的命令问东问西
Always apart. Always askin' why you should be doin' what you told.
你从来不是我们的一份子 也永远当不了
You was never one of us. You never could be.
我的头发看上去怎么样 Mike
How my hair look, Mike?
美极了 妞儿
You look good, girl.
他们说拿到加班费的人
They're sayin' the only O.T. That anyone has been seeing has been
都是通过查那起流浪汉杀人案
through getting detailed on the homeless killings.
- 他们说那才是要查的案子 - 没有设监听器?
- They say that's the case. - And no wiretaps up?
我问过了 我听小道消息说
I asked about that. And I'm hearing, off-the-record kinda,
的确装了监听器
that it was a wire.
这也说得通 因为Lester就爱搞这套
And it makes sense, 'cause that's how Lester works.
他搞到电话号码 把监听这条道走到黑
He gets hold of a number and works it to death.
他从哪儿搞来的号码我就不知道了
Where he would get the number I have no idea...
但搞监听是要日夜加班的 你又说没人在拿加班费
But a wiretap is hours, and you say no one is making any money...
这操蛋警局比我印象中的还要操蛋
Fuckin' department's more fucked up than even I remember it.
你去哪儿了 Mike
Where you been at, Mike?
你得来看看这个 有个连环杀手 但他只杀别的连环杀手...
You gotta see this. There's a serial killer, but he only be killin' other serial killers...
- 听着 我们去兜兜风 - 你这么慌干什么
- Yo, yo. We about take a ride. - You ain't got no whip.
快把你的东西收拾好 快点 我们得抓紧时间
Just gather your stuff. Come on, we gotta move quick.
- 快去 动起来 - 好吧
- Come on. Let's go! - OK.
但那就意味着 所有打给报社的电话
But that means... All the calls to the newspaper.
失踪者的图片
The photographs of the missing man.
- 我们明明装了窃听器啊 McNulty要窃听... - 一部手机
- We have a wiretap. McNulty has a... - On a cellphone.
我的天呐
Jesus Christ.
- 他不敢这么做的 - 电话号码是多少
- He wouldn't dare. - What's the number?
在文书里
It's on the paperwork...
- 走吧 - 去哪儿
- Come on. - Where...
证物管理科
Evidence control.
我一直以为你说 你有个阿姨住在这儿是在瞎扯
I always thought you were bullshittin' 'bout havin' an aunt out here.
她在等他
She expectin' him.
还有这盒子里的钱
An' what's in this box.
这里挺好的 对不
It's nice here, huh?
该走了 Bug
Let's go, Bug.
真希望我能跟你一起走 你会有自己的房间
Wish I was going with you. You gonna have your own room.
她可能还有台等离子电视呢 还有冲水的厕所
She probably got one of them plasma TVs, too. Them joints is wet.
我们走吧
Let's go.
好了 把这个交给Carla阿姨
OK, give that to Aunt Carla.
告诉她要是需要的话 我还会再给的
Tell her there's more behind it when she finds the need.
好吗
A'ight?
记得让她给你添几件新衣服
Make sure she cop you some fresh things, too.
我可不想你去新学校还穿得那么寒酸...
I don't need you going to a new school lookin' all...
哭什么呢 男儿有泪不轻弹
Come on, now. A man don't be sheddin' no tears.
去吧 Bug
Go on, Bug.
用完后放回前台去重新封装 好吗 长官
Bring it up front for re-seal when you're through, would ya, sir?
谢谢你 Augie
Thanks, Augie.
- Augie 我很高兴你找到了好出路 - 是啊
- Glad you landed OK. - Yeah.
总比干活好
Beats workin'.
为什么来这里
Why here?
为什么想跟这帮家伙混在一起 哥们
Why you wanna mix with their kind, man?
他们给了我工作
They give me work.
你骗谁呢
Who you talkin' to?
我知道他们在那里面干什么勾当 Duke
I know what they be doin' in there, Duke.
那我还继续跟着你
I could still hang with you, then.
你知道很多人想要我的命
You know I'm too hot.
你还记得那天吗 夏末那天
You remember that one day, summer past?
我们把灌尿水球扔到 Terrace那帮家伙身上
When we threw them piss balloons at them terrace boys.
你肯定记得 就在开学前
You remember? Just before school started up again...
你知道 我被那群家伙揍了一顿
Y'know, I took a beatdown from them boys,
但是我一点也不后悔
I don't even throw a shadow on it.
好难忘的一天
That was a day...
你们还给我买冰欺凌吃
Y'all bought me ice cream off the truck.
你记得吗 Mike
You remember, Mike?
不记得了
I don't.
后会有期 Mike
See you 'round, Mike.
再会 Duke
See you, Duke.